Michael Clark

Software Engineer

Bellevue, WA | 347-536-9958 | mikec7592@gmail.com | made-by-mike-73.vercel.app/ (Portfolio site) | github.com/mikec7592 | linkedin.com/in/mikec7592/

SUMMARY

Software Engineer who is a fanatic for helping others. My attention to detail and adaptability as well as my ability to pick up nuances missed by most can be attributed to my many years of competitive gaming. The skills I've acquired help me better collaborate on projects in order to reach higher levels. Through creating products that ease peoples' minds I am able to sate my appetite when it comes to helping others while also producing high quality results.

Skills

- Languages | Javascript, HTML, CSS
- Libraries and Frameworks | React, Node.js, Express.js
- Database | PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Mongoose
- Other | RESTful Routing JSON, AWS S3, Github

PROJECTS

Made_By_Mike | Personal Portfolio
Javascript | Next.js| Node.js | Tailwind CSS 07/2023-07/2023

- ❖ Personal portfolio React app using Next.js and Tailwind CSS.
- ❖ Fully responsive and mobile friendly featuring custom cards and a custom image carousel component.

YelpHikes | Hike rating Web App Javascript | HTML | Bootstrap | MongoDB

04/2023-05/2023

- ❖ A web app to rate and comment on popular hikes/campsites or to create a newly found one.
- ❖ Authentication via Passport and password salting for an extra level of protection.
- ❖ Interactive map so that a user can see what logged sites are in their area or search a specific area to plan an excursion.

ApexBattleTracker | Game/Stat tracker Javascript | React-Native | CSS | MongoDB

07/2022-10/2022

- ❖ User signup and login with encrypted passwords using JWTs.
- Standard CRUD functions to track your stat trends throughout play sessions.

EXPERIENCE

Progressive, Lynnwood, WA - Claims Adjuster Generalist

October 2022 - March 2023

- Took ownership over up to 50 claims and helped resolve client issues and claim concerns via email, phone and or text.
- Triage claims based on urgency/severity and escalate to appropriate parties when needed resulting in the resolution of over 5 claims per day.
- Documented all communications with clients and updating their info and concerns as they arise while ensuring the integrity of their confidential info remains uncompromised.

USPS, ISC JFK Queens, NY - Motorized Equipment Operator

October 2016 - July 2022

- Met with team members to go over our daily action plan and address potential blockers.
- Entered information into GBS database to update current and upcoming trip manifests and status reports.
- Worked with other operators to come up with a plan which ultimately reduced the number of round trips we had to make daily by nearly 40%.

Walgreens, Brooklyn, NY & San Diego, CA - Shift Supervisor

April 2012 - January 2016

- Created a task list at the beginning of shifts based on the condition of the store.
- Reviewed and resolved customer complaints/concerns and questions in real time as well as from the previous day.
- Created and taught others a technique to get an accurate read of inventory data that won't be affected by ongoing operations.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Brainnest Consulting, Berlin, Germany — Frontend Development Industry Training Remote

September 2022 - November 2022

General Assembly, New York, NY — Software Engineering Immersive Remote | 420 Hours

January 2021 - April 2021

John Jay College, New York, NY — Classes towards BS Forensic Science

August 2010 - September 2014